<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Guillaume Grandineau Blog</title>
    <link>https://guillaumeg9153.github.io/MyBlog/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Guillaume Grandineau Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 06 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://guillaumeg9153.github.io/MyBlog/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Lecture 1</title>
      <link>https://guillaumeg9153.github.io/MyBlog/posts/lecture1/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://guillaumeg9153.github.io/MyBlog/posts/lecture1/</guid>
      <description>Affordances : Good example : gear level :
Just by looking at the scheme on the gear level we instantly know how to use it. In fact, when the car is in neutral gear, just by looking at the scheme you understand that you have to put the gear level in the upper-left corner, and it’s the same when you want to shift gears even if we can’t see the mechanical pattern.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Guillaume Grandineau presentation</title>
      <link>https://guillaumeg9153.github.io/MyBlog/posts/presentation/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://guillaumeg9153.github.io/MyBlog/posts/presentation/</guid>
      <description>Hi Everyone ! Welcome to my blog, my name is Guillaume Grandineau and I’m a student in 3rd year at Telecom SudParis where I study High Tech Imaging, I’m also a student at Institut Polytechnique de Paris in a Master 2 named “Virtual and Augmented Reality”.
Here you can find some lectures and labs I did in this master, check out the contents, you could learn some interesting things.
As a filmmaking, cinema and photography passionate I also give you here a link to my portfolio : https://drive.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lab 1</title>
      <link>https://guillaumeg9153.github.io/MyBlog/posts/lab1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://guillaumeg9153.github.io/MyBlog/posts/lab1/</guid>
      <description>This game project was easy to follow since we already had labs on Unity before in order to build our proper game. First of all, building the objects that compose the game was the first task and as I said it was a quick task and this is how I did it.
So the scene is composed by a ground and 4 walls (I created an empty game object that parented them), on this board game I added a ball that will be our player and cubes that will be our collectibles.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lab 2</title>
      <link>https://guillaumeg9153.github.io/MyBlog/posts/lab2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://guillaumeg9153.github.io/MyBlog/posts/lab2/</guid>
      <description>This second lab is about the same game than the previous one but it’s a different way to play it since we built it for android devices. So the new gameplay is the following one : we no longer control the ball it’s the gyroscope of our phone that controll the board game (wall and ground). This is you your ground need to parent all of our game objects to the ground like this.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lab 3</title>
      <link>https://guillaumeg9153.github.io/MyBlog/posts/lab3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://guillaumeg9153.github.io/MyBlog/posts/lab3/</guid>
      <description>This new lab is still about the roll a ball game but this time we no longer use our phone to control the game board, this time we will be able to grab it with our hands thanks to VR. It was the most difficult labs of the 3, firstly, we had to import an oculus package to enable VR. Note that I used an oculus quest so I had to build the game like an android game.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lecture 2</title>
      <link>https://guillaumeg9153.github.io/MyBlog/posts/lecture2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://guillaumeg9153.github.io/MyBlog/posts/lecture2/</guid>
      <description>Lecture 4 : Let me introduce you Jonathan Grudin who is an American HCI researcher, he works as a principal design researcher at Microsoft and he is also a professor in the University of Washington Information School. He became famous since he received an award from the CHI Academy which is a group of people specialized in Human-Computer Interaction and since he is a pioneer of this field. As he worked on CSCW (Computer Supported Cooperative Work) he raised something that we will call later the “Grudin Problem” which explain why CSCW application fail and this is what we will deal with.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lecture 3</title>
      <link>https://guillaumeg9153.github.io/MyBlog/posts/lecture3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://guillaumeg9153.github.io/MyBlog/posts/lecture3/</guid>
      <description>Here are my ideas about AR :
Firstly I think AR is here to help us in our daily but I also think it has to be intuitive and look cool in order to be use often. My first Idea would be a kind of augmented mirror. Let me explain that : as the textile industry is one of most polluting one, some companies are trying a new system using pre-orders and then the company produces a number of clothes wich corresponds to the number of pre-orders.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lecture 4</title>
      <link>https://guillaumeg9153.github.io/MyBlog/posts/lecture4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://guillaumeg9153.github.io/MyBlog/posts/lecture4/</guid>
      <description>Lecture 10 : As you can see on the pictures I provided, Apple as well as Samsung have done pretty much the same innovations concerning the design of their smartphones. Firstly, and at the different of previous mobile phones, smartphones just had 3 maximum physical buttons at the bottom of their screen (without counting ones for the volume or the power). Then for the next generation the screen just got bigger (larger and longer), then this screen became borderless on his sides such as the Samsung galaxy s6 edge.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Unity Lab</title>
      <link>https://guillaumeg9153.github.io/MyBlog/posts/unity_lab/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://guillaumeg9153.github.io/MyBlog/posts/unity_lab/</guid>
      <description>In this Topic I will present you my Unity game named Floor is Lava 2k20. The game is separated in 4 rooms.
Here is the first one : This room is like a tutorial since it makes you understand that you need all collectibles in a room in order to remove the wall that is blocking you the access and that if you fall on the lava you respawn at the beginning of the zone.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
